hey's up guys My Name Is AO today I'm
going to be showing you how to properly
set up a C++ project especially one that
has this kind of core app architecture
which basically means that you have this
core library of code and then one or
more applications that will use that
core library now that by itself is
obviously extremely subjective everyone
has their own way of doing things and in
this video I'm going to be showing you
my way of doing things and the use cases
for this core app architecture are
honestly endless you could use this for
so many things I use this architecture
when making walnut chat as an example
it's like a instant messaging chat
client thing and even Hazel my game
engine uses this same architecture in
fact it's a very very good fit for game
engines so in this video we're first
going to take a look at how to use this
template to make a brand new C++ project
but then I'm also going to be showing
you how to retrofit an existing project
and conform it to this architecture and
to this template and we're specifically
going to be doing that with the 2000
hour 2D game engine that I have been
been code reviewing as part of my code
review series for like three videos
already because this will greatly
improve that now typically when people
make new C++ projects if they are either
new to programming or to C++ or they're
inexperienced or whatever the reason
might be a lot of the times they will
just open Visual Studio as an example or
whatever ID they use and they will click
the new solution new project button
whatever and just they'll start from
there it seems logical like I don't
blame anyone for doing that it seems
logical and for a lot of cases I'm sure
it's fine but there's a better way it's
by using my template this sounds like
I'm selling this template this template
is completely free the link will be in
the description below if you want to
just skip me talking the problem is that
with C++ most of the time you want to be
using a build system now a build system
really like it's it's a term that that
has many definitions potentially because
a build system as the name implies is
supposed to basically take your raw code
files and build it into some kind of
product now an example of a build system
is cmake cmake will do that I prefer to
use something different called premake
the name basically explains what it is
pre make make itself is a build system
the whole idea of make is that you have
these things called make files you use
them to describe what your project is
and how it should be built and then you
run make to build the project premake
exists as a way to generate make files
because make itself is kind of an
interesting build system/ language and
it can be very veror and potentially
difficult to express yourself in make
versus something like premake which just
uses lure and is much much much simpler
now pre-make doesn't just generate make
files premake also generates well any
kind of project file you really need so
for example if you want Visual Studio
project files because you're going to be
compiling your application or your
project on Windows prake can do that for
you it will take your lure description
of your project and it will generate
Visual Studio project files and solution
files for you hopefully you're beginning
to see the power now because if I
instead want xcode files because I want
to build this on my Mac or I want I
don't know make files because I want to
build on Linux I can do all of this
there's plenty other supported build
systems and Ides as well so that now
means that instead of me having to
create project files in Visual Studio by
using the UI and then having them only
work on Windows or at least only work in
Visual Studio I can create create all of
the build configuration files for my
entire project in premake and then have
premake generate whatever project files
I need so that is what premake is we've
been using it since the beginning for
Hazel and it's been it's been really
good and this template also uses premake
to generate all of the project files
which is one of the reasons why this
template is a fantastic starting point
for crossplatform applications now
before we dive in and take a look at
this template and I show you how to
start a brand new simp plus project
using it if you want to learn computer
science and math then there's an
excellent free way you can do that with
the sponsor of this video brilliant.org
brilliant.org is an amazing website
filled with lots and lots of courses on
various stem topics now as I mentioned
they're an excellent place to start
learning computer science because all of
their courses are just really clean and
fun and efficient at teaching you
instead of just watching like boring
lectures with zero engagement you
instead have these widgets that you can
play with that that show you how things
work I think their math courses are a
fantastic example of this cuz you can
see like for example with Calculus how
stuff works visually and you can play
with it to see how the numbers actually
reflect how it works but then also
they'll quiz you they'll ask you
questions to make sure that you are
actually learning something and that you
can answer those questions and the range
of how advanced their courses are they
go down all the way to the beginning
with the Everyday Math course which is a
fantastic place to just ease into math
all the way up to like linear algebra
and calculus and guess what you can take
a look at all of this for free brilliant
have a 30-day free trial that you can
use to check out everything they have to
offer just go to brilli ./ Theo link
will be in the description below and if
you do go on to like it brilliant have
been nice enough to offer the first 200
subscribers 20% off an annual membership
huge thank you to brilliant.org as
always for sponsoring this video okay so
here is the C++ project St template the
link will be in the description below
I've spent a little bit of time here on
this ra me so that you can read it
that's what a read me is for but the
easiest way to use this is to click this
use this template button because that
just lets you create a new repository
with this as like the starting content
so let's actually go ahead and do that
I'm going to just call this new project
I'll make it private I'll click create
repository this won't take very long and
then here we have our brand new
repository it's called new project it's
generated from Project template and now
what I can do is I can just clone this
so I've got this local folder here we
can just do get clone and then paste the
URL there we go we've got all of it
let's open it and this is it you're
you're ready to go so the most important
thing you need to know is that inside
the scripts directory there is a setup
Windows batch file there's also one for
Linux as well didn't get around to
making one for Mac OS but I'm sure
that's not too difficult so all we have
to do is just double click on this batch
file you can see it's going to run
premake here and then if we go out
you'll see that we have a new project
solution file so this is in the root of
this project so if we open it here we
have in Visual Studio what this looks
like so we've got an app project we've
got a core folder inside the core folder
there is this core project we've got
some example files just some starter
content so inside app you can see I'm
just calling something from core a
function called print hello world which
will'll just do this so if we just hit
F5 on that there you go we've got we've
got an application mindblowing I know
now hear me out I actually think this is
a lot faster than if you set this up in
Visual Studio yourself if you did set
this up in Visual Studio there'd be a
lot more clicking and it would be Visual
Studio only whereas with this template
we have this great architecture here
where you can see app references core so
I'm I'm ready to go on that front I have
debug disc and release configurations
already set up and as you saw I can also
generate these project files on Linux
just into make files and then use make
to to build this or I could really
generate whatever else preix supports so
so that's kind of it that's ready to go
out of the box now you might not want
this to be called new project so how can
we edit this and how does it work in the
first place so in the route we have this
build. L file by the way the GitHub read
me explains all of this so you can just
read that if you want but since we're
here I'll show you so build. L if we
open that up you can see I should
probably get rid of this commment whoops
you can see that we have a workspace
definition so this defines kind of like
our Visual Studio solution you can put
some workspace wide build options here
I've just put some ones that we commonly
use on Hazel you can set a more custom
output directory because by default
it'll be in binaries and then the
platform name the configuration name and
then the project name so if you don't
like that you can change it here here
are the solution configurations and the
architecture and the start project if
you want to change this to some other
name like orange let's call it project
orange if we go back to the root here we
have app and core so if this was my like
I don't know orange core let me just
maybe close this first and orange app
inside these two folders are where those
projects go so my core project is in
here here's that vcx project file
generated from earlier here's all of my
source files inside the source directory
and here is the lure file that tell us
premake how to build this project or how
to generate project files for this
project so if we open this up inside a
text editor then here we have all of the
Project Specific configuration so here's
the name for example it's called core so
let me change that to Orange core that
might be something you want to customize
the version of C++ as an example you
could also change this by the way to C
so this doesn't just have to be used for
C++ but that is the the common use case
for it which files you want to include
so I might actually change this a little
bit because at the moment it only
supports hcpp which is what I use
commonly however if you use like HPP or
cxx or you want C files as well like you
can add all of these here might make
more sense to to make it into something
that looks like this in that case
there's the compiler include directories
here I mean really if you want to set
this up you can see that there's
specific things for Windows or specific
settings for debug release or
distribution configurations if you want
to see what's possible you can just
check out the pre-make documentation
I'll leave a link to that in the
description below so that's orange core
if we go back out we have orange app
same story with that as well you can see
that we have a project called app which
I can rename to Orange core you can see
by the way that this is a console app
whilst orange core is a static library
and also orange app which I accidentally
called orange core uh links to core so
we need to update this as well cuz
that's the name and then if we want the
include path to also work we have to
update that you can also just use
variables that's fine but typically
project names don't change that often so
I usually don't bother okay so now back
in the original build file so this is
like the one for the for the solution or
the workspace we just need to make sure
that we're including the right
directories here so we can call this
orange core and orange app and if I go
back and just rerun that setup file it
should regenerate all the projects now
you can see I have project orange being
the solution file and then if I open
that I have orange core and orange app
the one thing I did forget to change is
the start project so over here inside
the build you can see the start project
is still app that's why it incorrectly
set this one as the start project cuz it
didn't find one called app so let's get
rid of that and then if I just delete
everything all of the generated project
files and rerun this open up the
solution file then you should see orange
app as the startup project and we should
be able to run this as normal Okay cool
so yeah that's really all there is to it
it's just a really nice starting point
if you want to have a C++ project with
this architecture and so now let's have
a look at how we can apply this to an
existing project which is not using this
it's not just using no build system or
no project generation system just raw
Visual Studio project files it's also
not using this architecture at all there
is no app and core distinction It all
becomes part of a single Visual Studio
project so we're going to apply this to
that and fix all of that up and
hopefully make it a lot better all right
so here we have the project that we're
going to be applying this magic to this
is the 2000 hour game engine that I've
been code reviewing it's part of my code
review series link to this project will
be in the description below again we're
just using it as an example because it
happens to not have this architecture
implemented and also doesn't happen to
have a build system at all implemented
so I've checked out the project locally
here it is on disk this is the root of
the repository if we go into the engine
folder there's just a Sprite Engine
Solution file and if we open that we are
graded with this so we have a Sprite
engine project just a single project in
this entire solution and then inside
here
we have the engine but also this project
itself if we take a look at the
properties you can see it builds into an
executable file and this is the editor
for the project so you can see here if I
look at the main file with the main
function it starts off with a UI project
selector and this is where you can open
whatever project you want and then it
runs the engine and essentially the
editor for this engine now what about
the games what if you want to just run
the game so inside the Resources
directory and template there's another
solution called assets and if we open
this this solution you can see that it
again has a single project and it's just
called assets and that has some kind of
subset of the game engines source files
so you can see there is also a main file
looks similar but it doesn't have that
UI project selector and then if we open
up the base Engine Solution which is the
editor if we take a look at these Source
directory side by side here you can see
that this one doesn't have for example a
GUI components section at all and I
think everything else looks pretty much
the same but see like in manager there's
a GUI manager here I don't know if it's
just in a different okay so it's here
but it's not included cuz I'm in show
files mode sure so there are some
differences as you would expect because
one of the project files builds into the
runtime one of the project files builds
into the editor so there have to be some
differences and they're definitely here
but what's really annoying about this
approach which I talked about in those
code review videos is this basically the
fact that since you have two different
projects all of these settings are
obviously per project right so these
settings and these settings they're two
different projects that need the exact
same settings more or less anytime you
want to link a new library anytime you
want to add an include directory anytime
you want to add like a pre-processor
definition that has to happen in both of
those projects and in fact every time
you want to add a file I just want to
add a new CPP file well if you wanted to
compile for both the game and the editor
as part of the engine then you have to
manually add it to both project files
which is very inconvenient so part of
the way that this core app architecture
helps you here is that we can group all
of this common code into that core
project and then have two different app
projects one which is this assets
project which is the game The Game's
runtime and then one which is this
Sprite engine project which is the
editor in those projects that falls
under the app project category we would
have things that are specific to those
applications and those projects but then
everything else that is core that is
Central to both of those applications
would be inside that core library inside
that core project now as an example when
we have something like GUI components
which is specifically part of the editor
in this case cuz it doesn't exist over
here inside the game project that could
simply just live inside that app project
that we'll make not inside core because
it's not going to be Central in more
specific setups this hierarchy of like
we have core and we have app can
definitely be extended by the way so you
could make another static library in
between core and app that's called like
GUI components and then that way if you
do need to reuse that code you can reuse
it in multiple applications so maybe you
have an editor but then maybe you also
have some kind of other tool that needs
to use GUI that would be a great example
of making like a GUI components project
in between core and app so that you can
reuse that code and then the game
project which doesn't need that would
simply Direct directly linked to core so
again I want to stress this template is
just a starting point and you can
definitely extend it okay so here we
have my project template all you have to
do is clone that somewhere I'm not going
to spend too much time on this here
because we've already covered this
earlier in the video but here I have the
physical files on disk what I'm going to
do from here just as a starting point is
just copy all of these files into this
Sprite engine UI project and I'm going
to have a look here as to where I want
this to live because there's this GitHub
directory with a couple images and then
there's the engine and I'm assuming this
person is trading the engine is like the
root directory so I think this would be
a good place for this to be pasted into
we don't need to get ignore and the read
me and the unlicensed I'm just going to
delete all of that so now we can really
begin customizing this stuff so the
source directory includes all of the
stuff that is relevant to the engine but
then there's also this Sprite engine
file and GUI components which seems to
be only relevant for the editor so as a
starting point I'm just going to grab
everything inside the source directory
cut it put it into core and then Source
I'm going to delete this St a content
content that we had here paste that in
there so now it's in here now I'm going
to rename core to Sprite engine core and
then app I'm going to call Sprite engine
editor and I'm going to copy and paste
that folder and just call it Sprite
engine runtime so we've got the core
we've got the editor and we've got the
runtime three different projects now if
I open this build. L file in a text
editor that's the one that's in the root
of this project I've got a group here
called core which runs build core we've
changed this directory name so I'm just
going to make sure we do that and then
we've got Sprite engine editor and
runtime so I'm just going to make sure
that we have two of these one's going to
be inside Sprite engine editor I might
call this something like build editor so
we'll have to rename that lure file as
well and then we also have Sprite engine
runtime and I'm going to call this build
runtime other than that that looks
pretty good I'm pretty happy with that
the start project we might make um the
editor so we'll have to name the project
that as well and then coming back into
here let's start with core I'm going to
go ahead and open this so over here
let's go ahead and call this project
Sprite engine core by the way we should
probably name the workspace something
thing I'll just call it Sprite engine so
what I'm doing here is I'm making a
workspace but I've got two different
projects tied into that workspace well
two different executables and then one
core Library you could make two
different solution files as well if you
wanted to you could just have another
workspace called like Sprite engine run
time and then another one called Sprite
engine editor that way you don't have to
have them all inside one solution if you
don't want to I prefer having them all
inside one solution because then you can
easily switch between the editor and the
runtime as you're developing the engine
so I'm going to leave it this way but if
you wanted two different Solutions you
could also set that up pretty easily so
here's Sprite engine cord that's going
to be a static Library just going to
include everything inside here I'm going
to set it as an include directory most
of these settings are pretty
straightforward and Universal like I
don't really need to change anything at
all so if we go back now I just need to
make sure that build core is called the
right thing so it is build core but then
we'll have to just rename editor and
runtime this is called build app so
let's rename it to build editor. lure
we'll go ahead and open it the project
name I'm going to call Sprite engine
editor it's going to be a console app
now if you wanted to you could make it
so that under filter distribution it was
set to uh Window app so I actually had
to open up the pre-make documentation
here but you can see these are the the
possible values of kind so we're using
static Library if you wanted a DL you
could use Shar lib instead and then
console app is just an application with
an actual console being allocated and
then if you didn't want that you could
have it set to Window app so Hazel for
example has release and debug set to to
console app because we use those two
configurations in development but then
the distribution configuration is set to
Window app so that's where these filters
really do come in handy as well now we
have to include the core directory if we
want to be able to include those files
so I think the directory is just Sprite
engine core and I think that's like for
now that's probably it if I go back
we'll just have to do the same thing
with the runtime so we'll call it build
runtime we'll pop that in here and then
I'll just make sure that we have that
same include directory as well as the
project being called Sprite engine
runtime uh the other thing is what it
links so it needs to link the Sprite
engine core project so you need to get
that name right obviously so Sprite
engine core is what both of these guys
need to link uh and then I think that's
it honestly for the project
configuration if you separate the files
into their proper directories meaning
the stuff that's relevant to the editor
you put into editor and vice versa you
shouldn't really have to do anything
specific here another thing we could
have done is just ignored certain files
so you can include an entire directory
but then exclude files as well that can
be useful under certain configurations
if you don't want to include debug files
inside a disc build for example but
we're not going to cover that here
because it's just not relevant back
inside core I want to have a look at the
GUI components and then also this Sprite
engine file because this Sprite engine
file is the thing that launches this UI
project selector because it's the editor
so this obviously shouldn't be in core
it should be inside that editor project
so I'm going to grab Sprite engine. CPP
and GUI components this file in this
folder I'm going to cut this and I'm
going to put it into Sprite engine
editor source so there's we'll delete
app Dopp which is just like the starter
content and we'll paste that in I
probably rename this file to something
like Sprite engine editor as an example
but this is what contains the main
function for this executable project so
that's inside source that's great now we
need to do the same thing for runtime
but remember that that's inside like
resources template engine I guess source
and then here's the main so I'm assuming
these are the same like we might have to
grab header know of headers necessary
but let's grab main I'm just going to
open up another view here we'll go back
to Sprite engine runtime Source we'll
delete app we'll paste this in we'll
call this Sprite engine runtime instead
of just main now going back here though
uh header was header something that we
had inside the core engine no so I'm
assuming we probably want that I don't
know what's inside there but I can see
that it's just in the runtime so we'll
paste that in and we'll see what happens
that was probably an include directory
by the way the way I'm doing this is
like this is a fair small project so I
don't really need to stress too much but
if I was trying to do this a little bit
more accurately perhaps there's a couple
ways I could go about that first of all
if we go into this template solution I
could open this as well as dropping in
this vcx Pro into a text editor just to
see exactly you know what files are
included in the build what pre-processor
definitions there are for various things
it's potentially a little bit easier to
just look at the text here and you can
see like for example what it links which
we're going to have to set up as well
obviously L but you can also do that
just using the UI if you prefer so if I
go into cc++ there's additional include
directories and you can see these are
the include directories that are
necessary so I obviously need to make
sure that these are all set up correctly
as well as inside Linker there's going
to be the additional Library directories
which I'm going to need to include as
well and then under input there are all
of these files all of these Library
files that need to get linked and there
are different variants so you can see
these have /d for debug but then if we
switch to release there's no - D sorry I
said SL D I meant - d That's not in
these ones so that's another example
where we would use filters but before we
do linking let's do compiling first
that's a good way to break this down
otherwise it's just too much at once so
in this runtime project if I just go
over here I know that I'm going to need
all of these directories included and
that's going to be relative to the
solution directory which is this
directory over here with that solution
file so we have engine and then we have
the source directory and that's included
as well as source include as well as
scripts as well as source include I am
goey so let's go back to build runtime
over here I'm just going to move it here
so I can see these two and then into
this include directory I've already got
Sprite engine core source which is this
directory up here so let's duplicate
that a couple times and we're going to
have source include now this scripts
directory is not part of the engine it's
inside assets we'll take a look at that
in a minute but we also have source
include I am goey as an include
directory so we'll add that and then we
have scripts So What on earth is in
scripts scripts doesn't actually exist
at the moment scripts is probably the
directory for like user scripts so if if
your game has custom CPP files I imagine
that's what that is because I think C++
is used as a scripting language so if
you wanted that you could of course also
have this here as an example so I'll
just leave that for now and then let's
also make sure that we have all of the
ones that are inside the engine so if we
open up the engine solution and we take
a look at these property Pages then we
have all of these guys so let's go ahead
and include all of this and you can see
there's some stuff here that's relative
to GUI components and some stuff here
that is relevant to uh the actual engine
so this is also by the way where I
should mention that it can get a little
bit difficult to discern what is part of
the engine and what is part of the app
so what's core what's app because
they're all in one project right so I
actually don't know if include IM guey
for example is necessary for the app
like it might just be something that the
core Library needs and same with include
like I don't know include sounds like it
should be included Source I guess as
well but if we go back into the core
what I'm going to do is make sure that
we also have Source SL include include
and source include I am guey and Source
headers so source include I am guey and
Source headers so we're putting these
include directories into the actual core
library because I'm assuming that the
CPP files there would need these include
parts to build and then if we go into
the editor configuration file then these
gii component ones are probably going to
be there and again some subset of these
possibly all of them I don't know so
let's just add I guess all of them so
source include include I am goey Source
headers and then we have a bunch of
stuff that's gii components which
remember is in our project now not
inside core so Source gii components
property editor real time editor project
selector okay that looks good um if we
take a look at the pre-processor so
again I'm just focusing on compiling
first not linking yet so this tab is
what I'm interested in not the link up
so inside pre-processor I also want to
make sure that these are set I guess
debug and console and then we have n
debug and console I don't know if
they're actually used by this project
cuz these are kind of Visual Studio
default pre-processor definitions but if
you wanted to add these two then
obviously into either debug or release
we could add them so for example release
see I've got release as just a a default
Define but doesn't look like we need it
so we can just replace it with n debug
and then this one would have underscore
debug and then disc we don't really have
a disc to begin with and then there's
also underscore console that's used in
all of these configurations so we could
just pop it down somewhere up here like
so and there we go so let's make sure
that build runtime also has this and
build core has this and then this n
debug uncore debug stuff I'm also going
to make sure that we have inside the
other projects and I think that should
be it as far as compiling goes obviously
it's not going to link but it should be
a good starting point so if we go back
to the rot uh and actually inside the
engine directory where we have this
script directory if we go ahead and take
a look at what setup Windows does you
can see it goes back a directory and
then calls this the file it's going to
run is build. L and it's going to
generate Visual Studio 2022 solution and
project file so that sounds pretty good
I think that should probably work so
let's go ahead and run this there we go
so you can see it's generated core
editor and runtime project files as well
as the Sprite Engine Solution file so if
we go back we now should have Sprite
engine with a space which is good cuz
otherwise it would have overwritten this
one so let's double click on this and
this is our brand new solution so over
here you can see we have Sprite engine
editor as a start project which is great
we got core with all the stuff that's
included inside core and then we've got
editor just with gii components and this
Sprite engine editor file as well as
Sprite engine runtime with that headed
directory which I don't know if we
actually need but sure and then we've
got Sprite engine runtime here as well
so we got a few errors that looks like
but let's go ahead and build core first
of all I'll right click and hit build
again this isn't going to link at all
because this is just a static Library so
we're just going to make sure that our
stuff is set up correctly which you can
see it's not so UI tool buttons model
seems like it's necessary by Sprite
repository which is weird cuz I thought
that it wasn't being used because I
guess this is something that is inside
GUI components but it's also inside
Sprite repository which is a very core
file as we learned from the code review
videos and see there's like editor Tools
in here so this might require a little
bit more work to actually properly
segregate but what I want to do is I
want to go back to this template cuz are
these files actually different imagine
if they were different so Sprite
repository. it's located over over here
inside manager let's take a look at it
here oh man it's a different file look
it doesn't have that these are full on
different files H okay so that's
definitely putting a dent into this I
mean they're probably not that different
but you can see editor tools isn't um
included in here it's got it looks like
it's basically the same thing but editor
tools you can see is not in here now I'm
expecting that the CPP file is also
going to be different because obviously
if this is a member variable I'm
assuming it's going to be used here
somewhere we go back to core and we take
a look at Sprite repository CP inside
core you can see there's current tool
and then well it's not really used
inside here but it is set here now
fundamentally I have no idea why Sprite
repository which is supposed to be
essentially a data structure would have
an editor tool inside it that again is
not a very good design and you can see
why it's leading to problems here where
we have to have two different Sprite
repositories where the only difference
really seems to be this current tool and
there's also this initialized kind of
word that's that's missing and otherwise
I think they're pretty much the same the
same file I could definitely make an
entire video talking about how to set
this up properly so that you could have
specific variance potentially of this
that only were used for a particular
project but then not another project so
for example like for the editor but not
for the runtime now there's some other
uh problems here and you can see that
actually a lot of this seems to just
rely on this gii components even though
I really thought it was excluded let's
go back to the template for a second and
we'll open up this solution did these
just not have any mention of
GUI there's GUI manager here but I guess
that doesn't but I guess GUI components
yeah it doesn't exist inside the
solution wow so every single file that
was in here has a variant has another
copy of that file that just has this
stuff manually stripped out which means
that if you if you update any code
inside game engine what so there's two
different game engine files sorry this
is turning into a bit of a code review
but if I go back into here and this is
game engine Doh here it just doesn't
have
that what so these are just
fundamentally different what do I do
here I actually don't know what to do
here so I guess this is a good example
of where it can be a little bit
difficult to retrofit this core app
architecture when you have gone down the
two different paths too far I think from
here there are a few different
approaches you could honestly take the
better solution would just be to to set
this up completely differently where you
don't have two identical classes that
have to have different code depending on
if it's the editor or the runtime but
instead all of your truly common code
like this renderer I mean you can see
even just the namespace is different
well actually no they're both in that
namespace but this just has this for
some reason but anyway you would have
the common functionality inside say game
engine and then the stuff that is
relevant to the editor would just be in
like the editor application file which
could be a number of things it could be
it could even be a subass of this it
doesn't have to be but yeah I honestly
had no idea that these files were so
actually different I just thought I just
thought this project had a different
subset of files so if we paste back this
GUI components as an example and let's
just go ahead and rerun the setup script
to regenerate this project I'm assuming
now it will probably build unless we
need yeah so you can see there's also
the include path here so going back into
core we need to make sure that I guess
all of these are also include
directories inside core if we wanted to
build and then let's rerun that and then
let's try and build that okay so we got
an error over here now okay I have real
time editor editor here for some reason
whoops let's rerun that again and
there's some other errors that we have
here to iron out I think this is upset
about chart 8T cuz this is u8 it's
probably a C++ version thing one thing I
forgot to mention is that this we set to
C++ 20 right so that the the template by
default comes with C++ 20 as the CPP
dialect the cppp version but if we look
at the original it's C++ 17 so that's
definitely something you want to get
right otherwise you might have issues
like we are seeing here so let's
regenerate that again if I try and build
this file you can see this file succeeds
let's try and build the rest of the
engine we're getting there we're getting
there do we have any errors no here I'm
seems to be building as well which
means our include directories are set up
correctly and there we we go we've
successfully built this as a static
Library so I hope this was helpful to
you if you want to retrofit this
potentially into an existing project
there's still quite a bit of work for
this specific project to get it to work
properly with this new architecture
considering that it is just a mess when
it comes to the way that it's set up to
eventually build into two different
products if you would like to see more
videos on me fixing this project and
bringing it into this architecture and
just setting it up properly in this in
this more robust way definitely let me
know in the comments section below but
otherwise I hope you guys do enjoy my
template if you enjoyed this video
please don't forget to hit the like
button link to the template will be in
the description below it's just freely
available on GitHub and the license is
just unlicensed so feel free to do
whatever you want with it don't forget
to check out brilliant.org Theo and I
will see you guys next time goodbye